<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Emerson M. Del Ponte</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Emerson M. Del Ponte</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW12) in Norway</title>
            <link>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</guid>
            <description>I had the privilege to attend, as a newcomer, the 12nd ed. of the International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW) in Lillihammer, Norway, during early June 2018. We were in a relatively small group of 50 plant epidemiologists from several countries around the world that interacted in several ways during three days of presentations of talks and posters and time for discussion.
 Group picture taken at the Scandic hotel and one taken during the poster sessions.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the privilege to attend, as a newcomer, the 12<sup>nd</sup> ed. of the International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW) in Lillihammer, Norway, during early June 2018. We were in a relatively small group of 50 plant epidemiologists from several countries around the world that interacted in several ways during three days of presentations of talks and posters and time for discussion.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iew12-0.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote>
<p>Group picture taken at the Scandic hotel and one taken during the poster sessions.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>New knowledge and advances in the discipline were presented and the current status and future of the discipline discussed. I liked the good mix of scientists at various stages in their career, including a few students. I moderated an oral session and gave two talks. The first talk on my work in the field of phytopathometry, particularly methods related with development, validation and deployment of standard area diagrams (SADs) for aiding visual severity assessments.</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iew12-1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote>
<p>Interactive poster sessions</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The second talk was in a special topics session where I presented data on reproducible research practices (sharing data and codes) in Plant Pathology papers published in more than a dozen journals of the field. It was an opportunity to talk and promote Open Plant Pathology <a href="http://www.openplantpathology.org" target="_blank">OPP</a>, a community to foster open science practices in our field, to the plant epidemiologists present at the meeting.</p>

<p>I enjoyed very much both the scientific and social aspects of the meeting. There was also some <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23iew12&amp;src=typd" target="_blank">activity on Twitter #IEW12</a>. It was an opportunity to see old friends and make new ones - some that I have interacted only virtually via OPP. Finally, I propose to organize the next meeting and the group decided on the next venue for IEW13 being somewhere in Brazil during 2022. This will be the second IEW in Brazil. The first was held in Ouro Preto in 2001 and organized by Prof. Bergamin Filho. Look forward to seeing the epidemiology community interacting again in four year!</p>

<p><img src="/img/posts/iew12-3.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote>
<p>Social moment during the meeting</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>From reproducible research reports to Open Plant Pathology</title>
            <link>/posts/2018/05/from-reproducible-research-reports-to-open-plant-pathology/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/2018/05/from-reproducible-research-reports-to-open-plant-pathology/</guid>
            <description>During the last two years I became interested in embracing open science practices - open data, codes and access aiming at improving reproducibility of the research conducted in the lab. Since then, I decide that:
 All data and R scripts from our Lab&amp;rsquo;s papers should be made available on GitHub and permanently stored somewhere The analytical procedures should be documented as much as possible and capable of being fully reproduced by others Pre-prints should be posted in advance of manuscript submission for enhanced visibility, feedback and open accessibility  First steps My first reproducible report using a single R Markdown file was published by late 2016.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>During the last two years I became interested in embracing open science practices - open data, codes and access aiming at improving reproducibility of the research conducted in the lab. Since then, I decide that:</p>

<ul>
<li>All data and R scripts from our Lab&rsquo;s papers should be made available on GitHub and permanently stored somewhere</li>
<li>The analytical procedures should be documented as much as possible and capable of being fully reproduced by others</li>
<li>Pre-prints should be posted in advance of manuscript submission for enhanced visibility, feedback and open accessibility</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="first-steps">First steps</h2>

<p>My first reproducible report using a single R Markdown file was published by late 2016. I generated html outputs for a commented analysis for a <a href="https://emdelponte.github.io/paper-white-mold-meta-analysis/" target="_blank">meta-analysis paper</a>. The files are available for download at <a href="https://github.com/emdelponte/paper-white-mold-meta-analysis" target="_blank">GitHub repo</a> and, after installing the required packages, the entire report can be generated by kniting the <code>rmd</code> files to produce a single <code>html</code> output for visualization of the report.</p>

<h2 id="structuring-a-research-compendia">Structuring a research compendia</h2>

<p>After a few months, I was working on a new standard for organizing and documenting the research-derived data and R codes on GitHub. Inspired by a <a href="https://github.com/ropensci/rrrpkg" target="_blank">ideas from others</a>, I structured an R Markdown website for producing a readable version of a research compendium - a compilation of data and computer code to reproduce the results of a publication. This was my <a href="https://emdelponte.github.io/paper-FHB-Brazil-meta-analysis/index.html" target="_blank">first template</a> which was further modified and used in another recent analysis report for a <a href="https://emdelponte.github.io/paper-FGSC-fitness/" target="_blank">paper</a>. For this new one, the files were stored permanently at Open Science Framework (<a href="https://osf.io/c2mbr/" target="_blank">OSF</a>) and a <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/12/18/235895" target="_blank">pre-print was posted in BioRxiv</a> for enhanced visibility and accessibility. My suggested minimum combo is:</p>

<ul>
<li>Store the entire directory and files at <a href="https://osf.io" target="_blank">Open Science Framework</a> (OSF) or <a href="https://zenodo.org" target="_blank">Zenodo</a> (where you can get a DOI)</li>
<li>Host the files at a GitHub repo</li>
<li>Push the website files to <a href="https://www.netlify.com" target="_blank">Netlify</a> or GitHub pages.</li>
</ul>

<p>Although more <a href="makes a custom isolated computational environment for the project" target="_blank">complex structures</a>, such as distributing the compendium as R packages and making a custom isolated computational environment for the project (docker) can be developed, I preferred to keep it at a minimum. There are only four <code>rmd</code> files and two folders, for <code>data</code> and <code>docs</code> folder which contain the html output after kniting. A template for the research compendium is available for <a href="https://github.com/emdelponte/research-compendium-website" target="_blank">download</a>. Given the simplicity and appealing presentation, it seems to be getting some attention by other people who are using it for producing documents for the analysis.</p>

<p><br><br>
 <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align = center data-lang="pt"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Looking for a nice way to share your <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/research?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#research</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/data?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#data</a>. Build <a href="https://twitter.com/github?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@github</a> pages! Here is a great example by <a href="https://twitter.com/edelponte?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@edelponte</a> (<a href="https://t.co/33YGafBeWH">https://t.co/33YGafBeWH</a>) and here a neat tutorial <a href="https://t.co/bE1GLaWj9y">https://t.co/bE1GLaWj9y</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/NicholasStrayer?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NicholasStrayer</a>.</p>&mdash; Rene Heim (@ReneHJHeim) <a href="https://twitter.com/ReneHJHeim/status/998131865054785536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">20 de maio de 2018</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<br><br></p>

<h2 id="why-not-formalize-a-network">Why not formalize a network?</h2>

<p>Earlier this year, after hours of late night and early morning discussions (me in Brazil and Adam Sparks in Australia), we thought that an environment for discussing, sharing experiences and educating in open science and reproducible research practices was lacking for plant pathologists. We were able to identify a few other colleagues valuing the sharing of data and codes in plant pathology journals. Some of them have been already teaching <a href="http://grunwaldlab.github.io/Reproducible-science-in-R/" target="_blank">reproducible science in R</a> - workshop offered at the APS meeting in 2016 by <a href="http://grunwaldlab.cgrb.oregonstate.edu/" target="_blank">Grunwald&rsquo;s Lab</a>. A permanent space for bringing together these guys interested in sharing experiences and building capacity in reproducible research was envisioned.</p>

<p>We then invited a few colleagues to join a <a href="https://openplantpathology.slack.com/" target="_blank">Slack workspace</a> where we brainstormed and decided to found <a href="https://www.openplantpathology.org/" target="_blank">Open Plant Pathology - OPP</a>. OPP is a community of researchers from various backgrounds interested in adopting and promoting reproducible research practices using open source software, data and repositories. It has been a great opportunity to interact and know other people in the Slack workspace where ideas are flowing and collaborations on the rise. We just wrote a <a href="https://www.openplantpathology.org/post/2018-05-20-second-post-five-month-summary/" target="_blank">blog post</a> in OPP where we provide a quick summary of the first five months of OPP is presented. Get to know <a href="http://www.openplantpathology.org" target="_blank">OPP</a> and consider joining our community!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
