<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Emerson M. Del Ponte</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Emerson M. Del Ponte</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW12) in Norway</title>
            <link>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</guid>
            <description>I had the privilege to attend, as a newcomer, the 12nd ed. of the International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW) in Lillihammer, Norway, during early June 2018. We were in a relatively small group of 50 plant epidemiologists from several countries around the world that interacted in several ways during three days of presentations of talks and posters and time for discussion.
 Group picture taken at the Scandic hotel and one taken during the poster sessions.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the privilege to attend, as a newcomer, the 12<sup>nd</sup> ed. of the International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW) in Lillihammer, Norway, during early June 2018. We were in a relatively small group of 50 plant epidemiologists from several countries around the world that interacted in several ways during three days of presentations of talks and posters and time for discussion.</p>

<p><img src="/img/iew12-0.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote>
<p>Group picture taken at the Scandic hotel and one taken during the poster sessions.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>New knowledge and advances in the discipline were presented and the current status and future of the discipline discussed. I liked the good mix of scientists at various stages in their career, including a few students. I moderated an oral session and gave two talks. The first talk on my work in the field of phytopathometry, particularly methods related with development, validation and deployment of standard area diagrams (SADs) for aiding visual severity assessments.</p>

<p><img src="/img/iew12-1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote>
<p>Interactive poster sessions</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The second talk was in a special topics session where I presented data on reproducible research practices (sharing data and codes) in Plant Pathology papers published in more than a dozen journals of the field. It was an opportunity to talk and promote Open Plant Pathology <a href="http://www.openplantpathology.org" target="_blank">OPP</a>, a community to foster open science practices in our field, to the plant epidemiologists present at the meeting.</p>

<p>I enjoyed very much both the scientific and social aspects of the meeting. There was also some <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23iew12&amp;src=typd" target="_blank">activity on Twitter #IEW12</a>. It was an opportunity to see old friends and make new ones - some that I have interacted only virtually via OPP. Finally, I propose to organize the next meeting and the group decided on the next venue for IEW13 being somewhere in Brazil during 2022. This will be the second IEW in Brazil. The first was held in Ouro Preto in 2001 and organized by Prof. Bergamin Filho. Look forward to seeing the epidemiology community interacting again in four year!</p>

<p><img src="/img/iew12-3.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote>
<p>Social moment during the meeting</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
