<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emerson M. Del Ponte</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Emerson M. Del Ponte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW12) in Norway</title>
      <link>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege to attend, as a newcomer, the 12nd ed. of the International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW) in Lillihammer, Norway, during early June 2018. We were in a relatively small group of 50 plant epidemiologists from several countries around the world that interacted in several ways during three days of presentations of talks and posters and time for discussion.
 Group picture taken at the Scandic hotel and one taken during the poster sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am plant pathologist specializing in quantitative epidemiology and disease management (CV. Currently, I am Associate Professor in the Departmento de Fitopatologia at the Universidade Federal de Viçosa(UFV). I am responsible for teaching (plant disease epidemiology and data analysis) and mentoring graduate students of the Graduate Program in Plant Pathology.
Research in my Lab includes both simulation and data-driven modeling approaches (dry lab) and experimental/observational bench/field work (wet lab). The &amp;ldquo;dry lab&amp;rdquo; projects involve quantitative approaches for measuring disease and assessing crop loss assessment methods; modeling temporal progress and spatial spread across scales; assessing and predicting disease risk and using meta-analytic models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumé</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>I hold a DSc in Plant Pathology (Univ. Federal de Pelotas, 2004) with 2-year PostDoc training in risk assessment and prediction (Yang Lab, Iowa State University). Currently, I am Associate Professor at the Universidade Federal de Viçosa (UFV) where I have both teaching and mentoring (masters and doctorate) responsibilities. I currently lead a research Lab and chair the Graduate Program in Plant Pathology at UFV. Also, I serve the Brazilian Phytopathological Society as Editor in Chief of Tropical Plant Pathology (2017 to 2021) and the global plant pathology community by co-leading the Open Plant Pathology initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>