<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetings on Emerson M. Del Ponte</title>
    <link>/tags/meetings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetings on Emerson M. Del Ponte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/meetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW12) in Norway</title>
      <link>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018/06/international-epidemiology-workshop-iew12-in-norway/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege to attend, as a newcomer, the 12nd ed. of the International Epidemiology Workshop (IEW) in Lillihammer, Norway, during early June 2018. We were in a relatively small group of 50 plant epidemiologists from several countries around the world that interacted in several ways during three days of presentations of talks and posters and time for discussion.
 Group picture taken at the Scandic hotel and one taken during the poster sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From reproducible research reports to Open Plant Pathology</title>
      <link>/posts/2018/05/from-reproducible-research-reports-to-open-plant-pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018/05/from-reproducible-research-reports-to-open-plant-pathology/</guid>
      <description>During the last two years I became interested in embracing open science practices - open data, codes and access aiming at improving reproducibility of the research conducted in the lab. Since then, I decide that:
 All data and R scripts from our Lab&amp;rsquo;s papers should be made available on GitHub and permanently stored somewhere The analytical procedures should be documented as much as possible and capable of being fully reproduced by others Pre-prints should be posted in advance of manuscript submission for enhanced visibility, feedback and open accessibility  First steps My first reproducible report using a single R Markdown file was published by late 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>